# Server Rules

## Preamble

[color=#ff0000]DISCONNECTING FROM OR IGNORING/EVADING COMMUNICATION FROM ADMINS WILL RESULT IN AN APPEAL ONLY BAN.[/color] The job gets really hard when you refuse to talk to the Admins, just come to our [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color] and talk it out.

[color=#bb00bb]This is the only source of server rules that apply to Parkstation, which ideally has all the information any regular player should need.[/color] Please do not ever hesitate to ask either an Admin in [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] or in the [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color] server if you ever want clarification on the rules.

We do not have a wiki, instead we have (or will have) all the needed information available via Guidebooks (NumPad0), such as Space Law and Standard Operating Procedure. If we do not have some bit of information (how to do a job or how specifically to execute something a document says) you may ask an admin via [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] or ask other players via the [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] or [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] chat channels.

The overall intention for this server is to do MRP right. NRP behavior will be dealt with by Admins, and we will have a generally high expectation of players in terms of role-play. Note that this does not mean we expect you to memorize pages of lore, or to be a savant at improv and writing. The line drawn is we expect players to put in [color=#ffd700]effort[/color] and to be here with the mutual goal of having a fun time and telling an engaging story, as that's what we believe this game to be all about.

## Rules
Some rules have an [textlink="I" link="ParkRules"] at the start of them, clicking this takes you to extra information about the rule.

[color=#a4885c]0.[/color] [color=#a4885c]The[/color] [color=#ffd700]Golden[/color] [color=#a4885c]Rule.[/color] Admins may exercise discretion with rules as they see fit, providing punishments for anything not covered by the rules, since this document can't possibly be that long and be expected to be read.
    - If you try to argue specificity of the rules with admins try try to weasel out of a punishment (aka rule lawyering), you will get punished anyway, and likely even more.
        - If you do wish to argue about the rules constructively/provide suggestions, you may do so in the relevant [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color] channels.
    - Admins will be help responsible for misuse of this rule, if you disagree with usage you may mention the Head Admin(s) in [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color] within your ban appeal and they will judge.

[color=#a4885c]1.[/color] These are English servers, and you are expected to use English when communicating through any server-related channels.

[color=#a4885c]2.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule2"] Absolutely no hate speech or bigotry.

[color=#a4885c]3.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule3"] No engaging in explicit sexual acts.

[color=#a4885c]4.[/color] Any RP had with other players should be entirely consensual. There are no firm guidelines on appropriate conduct, but the [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] and [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] channels are freely available. If you make another player uncomfortable you will be held accountable within reason.

[color=#a4885c]5.[/color] Attempting to evade game or job bans will result in an appeal-only permanent ban.

[color=#a4885c]6.[/color] Don't use custom clients, exploits, or external programs to play, gain an advantage, or disrupt the round/server. This includes auto clickers and auto-hotkey scripts.

[color=#a4885c]7.[/color] Don't "multi-key" (using multiple accounts simultaneously). Users knowingly using multiple SS14 accounts will have all of their accounts banned.

[color=#a4885c]8.[/color] Do not ignore the [color=#DC143C]AHelp[/color] or abuse it by flooding it with garbage, checking for admins before stating a problem -- also called "asking to ask" (i.e. "hello?" or "any admins?"), or sending messages of no substance. All [color=#DC143C]AHelp[/color]s are sent to the [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color], which means we see everything.

[color=#a4885c]9.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule9"] Pick a realistic name that could appear on a birth certificate with at least a first and last name.

[color=#a4885c]10.[/color] Act like an actual human being on a space station. Do not use text speak or emoticons [color=#bbbbbb]IC[/color], and do not refer to [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] things like admins in-game. Remember that this is an MRP environment, and people are expected to try and react to situations realistically, even if it's not the "optimal" thing to do. What's good for Roleplay > What's good for Gameplay.

[color=#a4885c]11.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule11"] Don't be a dick. You are playing a multiplayer game with other people who want to enjoy the game.

[color=#a4885c]12.[/color] Don't communicate in-game/in-character information through methods outside of the game (such as talking in [color=#5865F2]Discord[/color] with other users actively playing about the game or by talking to your sibling across the room while you are both playing). This is referred to as "Metacomming" and it is strictly forbidden.

[color=#a4885c]13.[/color] Don't harass or target players across rounds for actions in prior rounds or for actions outside of the game (this is referred to as "Metagrudging".)
    - Annoying players for [color=#bbbbbb]IC[/color] reasons in the current round is fine; doing it across rounds or as a ghost role after they kill you is [color=#DC143C]not[/color].

[color=#a4885c]14.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule14"] Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge to gain an advantage (this is referred to as "Metagaming").

[color=#a4885c]15.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule15"] Don't immediately ghost, suicide, or cryostasis if you do not get an antagonist role (referred to as "Antag-rolling").

[color=#a4885c]16.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule16"] Do not unreasonably escalate situations; don't murder someone for slipping you, use common sense.

[color=#a4885c]17.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule17"] Don't rush for or prepare equipment unrelated to your job for no purpose other than to have it "just in case" (referred to as "Powergaming").

[color=#a4885c]18.[/color] Intentionally making yourself a major problem/annoyance/disruption for the crew or other players at large while not an antagonist is forbidden (referred to as "self-antagging").

## Command/Security

[color=#a4885c]19.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule19"] If you sign up for a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] or [color=#6494F0]Security[/color] role, you are expected to know the basics of the game, your job, and the job(s) you supervise, if any.

[color=#a4885c]20.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule20"] [color=#6494F0]Security[/color] should try to remain non-lethal and effect arrests.

[color=#a4885c]21.[/color] [color=#6494F0]Security[/color] are be expected to answer for use of lethal force. [color=#6494F0]Security[/color] will be expected to effect arrests on criminals and prevent them from dying while in custody, even if lethal force is used.

[color=#a4885c]22.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule22"] [color=#6494F0]Security[/color] are expected to protect detainees in their custody to the best of their ability so as long as it does not come to an unreasonable risk to themselves, the crew, or the station at large to do so.

[color=#a4885c]23.[/color] [color=#DC143C]Space Law, Standard Operating Procedure, and Alert Procedure are expected to be adhered to.[/color] These can be found in the Guidebooks (NumPad0). Reading both of these, especially as a [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] member, can provide great ways to deal with problems in certain cases.

[color=#a4885c]24.[/color] Any [color=#334E6D]Command[/color] members should [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] when they need to stop playing. Do not play these roles if you do not expect to be able to finish the round.

[color=#a4885c]25.[/color] [color=334E6D]Command[/color] members are expected to exhibit some competency. Incompetence can result in a job ban. [color=334E6D]Command[/color] roles are designed to lead and manage departments first. They are not intended to become do-it-all members of their departments.

[color=#a4885c]26.[/color] Crew promoted to acting heads of staff must step down when an official head of staff arrives at the station.

## Roleplay

[color=#a4885c]27.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule27"] This server is a "Roleplay Expected" server. We define this as performing your assigned duties, "doing your job". This means it is important to do what is expected of your department and not what would be expected of other departments.

[color=#a4885c]28.[/color] Each round exists independently of all other rounds. While friendships persisting through rounds is okay, using experiences from other rounds to give an advantage or disadvantage over other players is not permitted.

[color=#a4885c]29.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule29"] Do your best not to interact negatively with SSD/AFK players. Moving them to safety is acceptable; killing, looting, or otherwise griefing them while they are away is not.

[color=#a4885c]30.[/color] [textlink="I" link="ParkRule30"] Antagonists exist to move the round forward and make things interesting and fun for everyone involved. The point isn't to "win", kill everyone else, or anything like that.


## All users must be at least 17 years old
